Guide to the Victor Lloyd Butterfield Papers, 1910 - 1975
Victor Lloyd Butterfield Papers 1910 - 1975
- Butterfield Papers1910-1975
  - History & theory
  - Honorary degreees
  - Honors college
  - I
  - Internal revenue
  - Inauguration
  - Inaugurals
  - Inquiries
  - J
  - K
  - L
  - Library
  - Liquor
  - Long-range plans, comments VLB's letter (Box 113)
  - Long-range plans, interim report
  - M
  - Maps
  - M.A. ad eundem gradem
  - Matriculation
  - Memoranda
  - Merritt property
  - Middletown redevelopment (Box 114)
  - Mc
  - N
  - National Endowment for the Humanities
  - Name, change of
  - NAACP
  - Negroes
  - Negro program, upward bound
  - Nuclear center
  - O
  - P
  - Pentagonal (Pres.) at Bowdoin
  - Personnel Secretaries
  - Personnel Technical assistants
  - Personnel policies
  - Personnel salaries
  - Placement office (Box 115)
  - Policies, VLB's
  - Policies admissions
  - President's functions
  - President's report
  - President selection committee
  - President's staff
  - Provost's functions
  - Programs
  - Publications annual report
  - Publications Alumnus
  - Publications Argus
  - Publications catalog
  - Publications mid-winter bulletin
  - Publications newsletter
  - Publications
  - Public relations (Box 116)
  - Public affairs
  - Public relations
  - Public relations City College
  - Public relations parent's day
  - Q
  - Questionnaires
  - Questionnaire ro Wes alumni
  - R
  - Recommendations
  - Regrets
  - Religious center
  - Research
  - Retirement letter
  - Retirement employees
  - S
  - Science advisory board
  - Science center (Box 117)
  - Seal of the college
  - Science grants
  - Secretarial salaries
  - Speeches by VLB
  - Statistics
  - Students general
    multiple tabs within file
  - Student social activites (Box 118)
  - Student committee on university development (SCUD)
  - Student loans
  - Study of educational policies and programs (SEPP)
  - Summer intensive language institute
  - T
  - Television
  - Testimonial letters
  - Trustees address list
  - Trustees amendment to by-law
  - Trustees agenda
  - Trustees call to meeting
  - Trustees by-laws
  - Trustees alumni & public relations
  - Trustees budget committee
  - Trustees capital funds drive
  - Trustees committees
  - Trustees committee to name buildings
  - Trustees buildings and grounds (Box 119)
  - Trustees education committee
  - Trustees finance committee
  - Trustees fraternity committee (Box 120)
  - Trustees index of minutes
  - Trustees long-range plans
  - Trustees minutes
  - Trustees extra copies
  - Trustees nominations
  - Trustees reservation forms
  - Trustees student affairs sub-committee
  - Trustees trustee candidates
  - Trustees schedule for meetings (Box 121)
  - Trustees wives' names
  - Trustees upward bound program (see negro program)
  - U
  - V
  - Vacation trips
  - W
  - Vice-president for planning & development
  - Wesleyan in perspective
  - VLB's interviews, England, Scotland, Copenhagen
  - Wesleyan center A-Z
  - Wesleyan center tax and visa info for visitors
  - Wesleyan center general correspondence
  - Wesleyan scholarly press
  - Wesleyan men abroad
  - White House conference
  - XYZ
  - Xerox Corporation
  - Aitken, William (Box 122)
  - Agoston, Max
  - Albrecht, Felix
  - Allen, Archibald, W.
  - Ammon, Ulrich H.
  - Anagnostakis, C.
  - Anderson, Samuel W.
  - Arnault, Donald
  - Arnold, Herbert
  - Baierlein, Ralph
  - Balsley, James R.
  - Barber, William
  - Bartholomew, R.
  - Barlow, Jon K.
  - Bendall, Kent
  - Benson, Robert
  - Berry, Spencer
  - Birnbaum, Norman
  - Briggs, Morton
  - Boynton, Peter
  - Brockunier, Hugh
  - Brown, Robert
  - Buel, R.V
  - Burford, M.G.
  - Burns, John M.
  - Butler, Jeffrey
  - Chen, Yuh-Ching
  - Cherpack, Clifton
  - Churchill, William L.
  - Cochrane, Vincent (Box 123)
  - Cohan, George
  - Coley, William
  - Comfort, William W.
  - Cook, Samuel D.
  - Coppotelli, Arthur A.
  - Crampton, C.B.
  - Creeger, George
  - Crites, Stephen D.
  - Cronin, James
  - Daniels, Norman
  - deBoer, Fredrik
  - deBoer, Jelle
  - DeBold, R.C.
  - Dibble, Vernon K.
  - Durkan, Michael J.
  - Dyson, S.L.
  - Ebel, Henry
  - Eck, Thomas
  - Edgar, John B., Jr.
  - Ellis, Robert
  - Ferrari, Anasthasie
  - Firshein, William
  - Fletcher, E
  - Franz, Otto
  - Frazer, J.
  - Fry, Albert H.
  - Garrison, George
  - Gelb, Leslie H.
  - Gemeinhardt, L.
  - Golob, Eugene
  - Gomez-Ibanez, J. (Box 124)
  - Gortner, Ross
  - Gotthelf, Allan
  - Gottschalk, Walter
  - Greene, Nathaniel
  - Greene, Richard
  - Green, Samuel M.
  - Greenstein, Fred I.
  - Guy, James
  - Haagen, Hess
  - Hallie, Philip
  - Hallowell, Burton (Box 125)
  - Hanson, Earl D.
  - Hassan, Ihab
  - Heideman, Walter
  - Helfer, James S.
  - Henney, Thomas G.
  - Hill, Henry A.
  - Holzberg, J.D.
  - Hoy, John
  - Hurwitz, Isaac D.
  - Idzerda, Stanley
  - Johnson, Adrian
  - Kenney, H.F.
  - Kerr, William C.
  - Kidder, George W., III (Box 126)
  - Kiefer, Barry I.
  - Kilby, Peter
  - Kirkpatrick, Robert
  - Knapp, Robert
  - Kosinski, Maria
  - Kulik, James A.
  - Lawrence, Anne
  - Leaf, Russell C.
  - Lebergott, Stanley
  - Leermakers, Peter
  - Limbach, Russell T.
  - Lindquist, Richard
  - Linton, Fred
  - Lippincott, Richard
  - Long, Donald
  - Lowengrub, Morton
  - MacFarlane, Keith
  - Maguire, John
  - Martz, Charles
  - Marr, David E.
  - Martin, John
  - Matzinger, Heinrich
  - Matthews, Howard B.
  - McAllester, David P.
  - McIntosh, John S.
  - McCurdy, Hugh G.
  - Miel, Jan
  - Miller, Richard Alan
  - Mink, Louis
  - Mitchell, Al
  - Mohan, Pandiri
  - Moore, Basil
  - Morsello, Casper J.
  - Murphy, Geraldine
  - Murphy, Russell
  - Nadler, Harry
  - Nell, Edward J.
  - Nichols, David
  - Olson, Lawrence
  - Ohmann, Richard
  - O'Gorman, Herbert J.
  - Orland, George
  - Ormsby, Elizabeth L.
  - Page, Thornton
  - Parker, Wyman
  - Paton, John W.
  - Patrick, Baxter
  - Parsons, J.
  - Pendleton, Ralph (Box 128)
  - Peoples, Joe W.
  - Peterson, Cynthia W.
  - Plagenhoef, Stanley
  - Polsby, Nelson
  - Pomper, Philip
  - O
  - Reed, Joseph Jr.
  - Regalado, Nancy
  - Rendall, Raymond
  - Reynolds, Paul A.
  - Rhodes, Frank
  - Richter, Mel
  - Risley, John
  - Rodriques, Luis-Luis
  - Rogers, Robert N.
  - Rood, Herbert
  - Rosenbaum, Robert
  - Rudich, Norman
  - Russell, Allan
  - Russell, Donald
  - Salas, S.L.
  - Scheibe, Karl E.
  - Schlieman, John (Box 129)
  - Schultz, Arthur R.
  - Schwaber, Paul
  - Schwarz, Heinrich
  - Sease, John
  - Sebera, Donald K.
  - Shapiro, Norman R.
  - Sheliga, Irene
  - Shieh, Julia Ju-chie
  - Simmons, Ernest J., Dir. Center, 2nd sem.
  - Singleton, R.R.
  - Souza, Raymond D.
  - Spurrier, William
  - Stanford, Janice
  - Stabler, Ernest
  - Stedman, Murray
  - Spaeth, John
  - Swanson, Elmer
  - Swift, David
  - Tashiro, Tom (Box 130)
  - Tharin, James C.
  - Thiesmeyer, John
  - Tierney, James F.
  - Titus, David
  - Tokes, Rudolf
  - Tompkins, Daniel
  - Tong, Hing
  - Trousdale, W.L.
  - Twiss, Robert
  - Underwood, Kenneth
  - Vann, Richard T.
  - Viglino, Giovanni
  - Viggiani, Carl A.
  - Vila, George R.
  - Vogel, Robert C.
  - Vose, Clement
  - Wagner, Robert R.
  - Waldrop, Rosmarie
  - Wallace, Willard M.
  - Wasch, William
  - Ward, William R.
  - Weber, Robert
  - Wensinger, A.
  - West, Michael D.
  - Wheatley, James
  - Whitin, Thomson
  - Whitfield, Guy K.
  - Wilbur, Richard
  - Williamson, Edward (Box 131)
  - Winslow, Richard
  - Wood, John L.
  - Yon, Andre
  - Fellows: Center for advanced studies
  - Fellows
  - Center fellows
  - Post doctoral fellows
  - Research associates
  - Summer school
  - Faculty appointments, A-G (Box 132, Folder 1-6)
  - Faculty appointments, H-O (Box 133, Folder 1-5)
  - Faculty appointments, P-T (Box 134, Folder 1-5)
  - Faculty appointments, U-Z (Box 135, Folder 1-2)
  - A.B.C. (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Alumni fund (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Alumni association and council (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - Alumni complaints (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - Associations A-Z (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - Buildings & grounds (Box 135, Folder 8)
  - Business affairs; student loans (Box 135, Folder 9)
  - Colleges (Box 135, Folder 10)
  - Combined plans (Box 135, Folder 11)
  - CT state department (Box 135, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum; freshman year (Box 135, Folder 13)
  - Curriculum; humanities lab. (Box 135, Folder 14)
  - Curriculum; general (Box 135, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum; geography (Box 135, Folder 16)
  - Curriculum; geology (Box 135, Folder 17)
  - Curriculum; humanities 1-2 (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum; humanities 3-4 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum; humanities 51-52 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum; language lab (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum; pre-med (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum; public affairs (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum; Russian (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum; science 1-2 (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum; science 3-4 (Box 136, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum; social science 1-2 (Box 136, Folder 10)
  - D.E.F.G.H. (Box 136, Folder 11)
  - Discrimination (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Faculty advisory committee (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Faculty campus art committee (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Faculty chapel committee (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Faculty admissions (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Faculty art department (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Faculty astronomy (Box 137, Folder 7)
  - Faculty biology department (Box 137, Folder 8)
  - Faculty chemistry (Box 137, Folder 9)
  - Faculty economics (Box 137, Folder 10)
  - Faculty English (Box 137, Folder 11)
  - Faculty geology (Box 137, Folder 12)
  - Faculty mathematics (Box 137, Folder 13)
  - Faculty music (Box 137, Folder 14)
  - Faculty physical education (Box 137, Folder 15)
  - Faculty physics (Box 137, Folder 16)
  - Faculty psychology (Box 137, Folder 17)
  - Faculty religion (Box 137, Folder 18)
  - Faculty romance languages (Box 137, Folder 19)
  - Faculty sabbatical & leaves (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Graduate division; scholarly books (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Graduate division; school services and publications (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - I.J.K.L.M.N. (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Institute of ethics & politics (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Itinerary (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - Library (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - O.P.Q.R.S.T. (Box 138, Folder 8)
  - Trustees; buildings & grounds (Box 138, Folder 9)
  - Trustees; budget committee (Box 138, Folder 10)
  - Trustees; executive committee (Box 138, Folder 11)
  - U.V.W.X.Y.Z (Box 138, Folder 12)
  - Active trustees [1954-1967]
    - Andrews, Kenneth (Box 138, Folder 13)
    - Anthony, Julian (Box 139)
    - Baird, John W.
    - Beach, W.Waldo
    - Bischoff, Ralph
    - Bodine, John
    - Buckingham, Harold
    - Burr, Francis K.
    - Clee, Gilbert
    - Daddario, Emilio
    - Eldridge, D.A.
    - Fretwell, Elbert
    - Ingraham, H. Gardner
    - Johnson, Berkeley
    - Kiermaier, John
    - Macy, John W., Jr.
    - Maynard, Roger
    - McCabe, J.
    - McClelland, D.C.
    - O'Leary, James J.
    - Silloway, Stuart F.
    - Steele, Richard T.
    - Stone, Charles B.
    - Tooker, Sterling
    - Tyner, Ralph T.
    - Wells, John
    - Wenner, Frank H.
  - Trustees emeriti [1950-1967]
    - Bacon, C.Everett (Box 140)
    - Baldwin, Raymond E.
    - Boyd, Darrell S.
    - Brown, Philip
    - Burbank, Paul
    - Coffin, Vincent
    - Develin, James A.
    - Fricke, Alfred K.
    - Hancock, Steward F.
    - Inglis, Ernest A.
    - Laggren, Robert I.
    - Lehninger, Albert L.
    - Moe, Henry A.
    - Newell, F.B.Bishop
    - Parr, F.Van Siclen, Jr.
    - Parsons, Robert W.
    - Ryder, Frank H.
    - Skilton, George W.
    - Thornton, Stanley L.
    - Travis, H.G.
    - Welch, Herbert Bishop (Box 141)
  - Destroy file
    not empty
  - Speech: "The Faith of a Liberal College" (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - Speech: "Report of the President to the Board of Trustees and the Academic Council on the Future of the University" (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - Speech: 1959 Commencement (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - Speech: "Charge to the Graduating Class, University of Connecticut" (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - Speech: "Counter-Attach in Liberal Learning" (Box 142, Folder 5)
  - Speech: "Liberal Education and the Beginnings of Wisdom" (Box 142, Folder 6)
  - Citation for Honorary Doctor of Humane Letters degree awarded to V.L.B. (Box 142, Folder 7)
  - Speech: "The President's Report" (Box 142, Folder 8)
    Report to the Board of Trustees for 1966-1967
  - Speech: "The Life of the Teacher" (Box 142, Folder 9)
    An address delivered at the Twenty-Eighth Annual National Conference of the Secondary Education Board
  - [A report on V.L.B.'s twenty-first year of services to Wesleyan in the office of President] (Box 142, Folder 10)
  - Speech: "The Relations Between the Liberal Arts College and the Graduate School" (Box 142, Folder 11)
    Speech delivered at the Annual meeting of the Association of American Colleges in Atlantic City, NJ
  - Citation for University Honors, V.L.B. Doctor of Laws (Box 142, Folder 12)
  - Speech: "Creed of the Liberal College" (Box 142, Folder 13)
  - Speech: "Commencement Address" (Box 142, Folder 14)
  - Speech: "Inaugural Address" (Box 142, Folder 15)
  - Speech: The Dedication of the Butterfield Colleges, Response (Box 142, Folder 16)
  - Speech: "Charge to the Navy V-12 Graduates" (Box 142, Folder 17)
  - Speech: "Charge to the Graduating Class" (Box 142, Folder 18)
  - Speech: "Charge to the Graduating Class" (Box 142, Folder 19)
  - Speech: "Charge to the Graduating Class" (Box 142, Folder 20)
  - Speech: "Charge to the Class of 1954" (Box 142, Folder 21)
  - Speech: "Charge to the Graduating Class" (Box 142, Folder 22)
  - "Can We Improve Our Education for Leadership?" (Box 142, Folder 23)
    First program in "The Great Challenge" series for 1960 as broadcast over the CBS Television Network March 27, 1960
  - Speech: Excerpt from Butterfield Matriculation Address (Box 142, Folder 24)
  - Speech: "The Liberal Arts College - Its Dream and Its Reality" (Box 142, Folder 25)
  - Speech: "Alumnus" (Box 142, Folder 26)
  - "Liberal Learning and the Professions" (Box 142, Folder 27)
  - "Relations Between Undergraduate and Graduate Education in the Liberal Arts and Sciences. The Problem of Humanistic Scholarship (Box 142, Folder 28)
  - Speech: "If the Salt Have Lost Its Savour" (Box 142, Folder 29)
    Skidmore Address
  - Alumnus articles (Box 142, Folder 30)
  - Speech: Report of the President for the Academic Year 1962-1963 (Box 142, Folder 31)
  - A letter to all alumni (Box 142, Folder 32)
  - Speech: Matriculation (Box 142, Folder 33)
  - Summary of speeches and articles by and about V.L.B. (Box 142, Folder 34)
  - Miscellany, Notes (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 143, Folder 2-11)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 143, Folder 12)
  - Press releases (Box 143, Folder 13)
  - Retirement (Box 143, Folder 14)